Hey...
/Hey!
안녕
/안녕
Pheebs, what's wrong?
피비! 무슨일이니?
Oh, I'm just so exhausted
나 지금 미칠 것 같아.
from dragging around this...HUGE engagement ring!
약혼반지가 워낙 무거워서 말이지!
오! 이런 세상에!
- 축하해
OH! My God!
- Congratulations! Wow!!
So, did he get on one knee,
혹시 마크가 청혼할 때 무릎을 꿇고 했니,
did he have a speech prepared, or did he cry?
아니면 발언 연습을 했거나 혹은 울었니?
Yeah, big surprise,
I like proposals!
그래 나 프로포즈 좋아한다.
그게 놀랄일이냐?
Well, it was really sweet,
and like the most romantic thing ever.
대단히 귀여웠어.
평생 잊지 못할 날일 것 같아!
Well, hey! Well...Here's to Phoebe,
who's found the greatest guy in the world!
To Phoebe and...
피비를 위하여!
임자를 찾은 것을 축하하며 피비와....
I wanna say Mike?
그의 이름이 마이크였나??
To Phoebe and Mike!
피비와 마이크를 위하여!!
고마워
Thank you!
Oh, and I have something for you!
내가 너한테 보여줄게 있어
It's, yes, my little black book.
It's got the numbers of all the guys I've dated.
검은 색깔의 책인데,
내가 데이트를 했던 남자들의 전화 번호책이야.
Oh, Pheebs, baby, that's nice but, you know what, I think I'm ok.
피비 고맙긴 한데....난 괜찮거든...
Why don't you give it to one of your other single girlfriends?
혼자사는 다른 친구한테 주지 그러니?
그러고 싶지만... 너 뿐인데
I would, but you're the last one.
GIVE ME THE BOOK!
책이리줘.
파블로 디아스....
Pablo Diaz....
Brady Smith....
레이디 스미스....
huh, "Guy-in-van"?
가이 이벤...
Oh, my first love!
오! 나의 첫사랑!
What does the red X next to Bob Greenmore's name mean?
여기 빨간 색 채크 표시 다음에 있는 밥 그린몰은 무슨 뜻이니?
죽었다는 뜻이야.
Dead.
Oh, it's OK, no, he was old, yeah!
괜찮아. 그는 늙었거든...
And he lived a full life, he was in the first wave at Omaha Beach.
그는 완벽한 인생을 살았고, 오마하비치에 있었거든...
Hey, I'm sorry,
I should have given you guys my black book when I got married!
미안하다. 얘들아.
내가 결혼 했을 때 검은 색깔의 책을 주는 건데.
Although it wasn't so much a book as a... napkin.
책이라기보다는 냅킨조각이었지만...
With Janice's phone number on it.
제니스 전화번호밖에 없고...
피비! 레퍼리 롤런은 밴드 아니었니?
Phoebe, isn't Jethro Tull a band?
Oh yes, they are.
어! 그래! 밴드였어!
FㆍRㆍIㆍEㆍNㆍDㆍS
10x06. The One With Ross's Grant
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON NBC: 2003/11/06
자막제작 - 코리아닷컴 프렌즈 동호회 (http://club.korea.com/friends)
[ 번 역 ] 배종혁 (javsh@korea.com)
[ 싱 크 ] 변정주 (jungjoo@kaist.ac.kr)
[ 테스트 ] 박재은(pje817@korea.com)
[ 영문자막 ] 김영대(kiyora00@korea.com)
자막에 관련된 문의는 동호회에 있는
'자막 피드백게시판'으로 해주세요~
[ 게스트 ] 이상민(albileon@korea.com)
자막에 관련된 문의는 동호회에 있는
'자막 피드백게시판'으로 해주세요~
Hey honey!
안녕! 여보!
안녕! 자기!
Hi sweetie!
Is Monica not here?
/No.
모니카는 어디갔어?
/어!
Oh, then I'll tell you.
내가 말해 줄게 있어!
My agency was bidding for a big account and they got it!
우리 에이젼시에서 큰건을 잡으려고 노력했었거든.
우리가 그걸 따냈거든,
It's my first national commercial!
내가 처음으로 시작하는 전국 광고야!
Cool!
잘됐네.
Yeah, and I don't wanna brag but a lot of the ideas were mine!
그래. 이번에는 꼭 성공을 할 꺼야.
많은 아이디어가 있거든.
Hell, you weren't there? All the ideas were mine!!!
맞어 너는 거기에 없었지? 모든 아이디어는 내거야!
That's great! Hey, can you cast me in it?
잘됐네! 내가 그 광고에 출연을 할 수 없을까?
Oh... I don't know, I really don't think you're right for the part.
잘 모르겠는데, 너한테 맞는 역할이 없을 것 같아.
What do you mean? I can do anything,
I'm a chameleon! Huh?
무슨 말이야!　나는 무엇이든지 할 수 있어!
나는 카멜레온이란 말이야!
I'm old!....I'm tired!....
Hey, I'm hot....I'm cold!! Huh?? Come on! What can't I do?
늙었다....피곤하다....
덥다....춥다.... 봤지?
First of all. Bravo.
훌륭하다.
Uh, but I really don't think you're right for this.
The part calls for a stuffy college professor.
내가 생각하기에는 역할이 맞지 않을 것 같아.
그 역할이 일류 전문 대학교수이거든
나도 할 수 있다.
I can do that!
"Hello, I'm your professor.
"안녕하세요! 여러분의 교수입니다.
When I'm not busy thinking of important things or...professing.
저는 그다지 전문적으로 심각한 생각을 하지 않고...
I like to use..." Oh, what's the product?
저는 앞으로...오! 주제가 뭐였지?
Software that facilitates inter-business networking e-solutions?
인터 비지니스 네트워킹에 대한 솔루션 프로그램
... 춥다!
... I'm cold!
Hey!
/ Hey!
안녕
/ 안녕
Guess who's a finalist for a huge research grant!
누가 리서치 그랜트에 나가게 되었는지 알아 맞추어봐.
I'll give you a hint, he's looking right at you.
내가 힌트를 줄게! 바로 네 눈앞에 있어
흠. 그가 도대체 누구인지 궁금하네. 축하해
Ah, well, unless it's the creepy guy with his hand up his kilt,
I'm gonna say congratulations!
Oh, I'm so excited, I mean,
apparently I beat out hundreds of other applicants,
나 지금 너무 훙분된다. 신청자들이 100명이 넘었는데
included five guys I went to graduate school with.
Not that I'm keeping score or anything...
거기에다가 나까지 포함을 해서 졸업생들이 5명이거든
five!
"5명"
Wow, that's great! So, tell me about the grant!
와우! 아주 잘 됐다! 어떤 그랜트인데?
Well, ok, it's for 25 thousand dollars.
연구비 2만5천불이 달린건데.
And if I get it,
I'll finally be able to complete my field research!
만약에 내가 이긴다면 드디어 완전한 현장 조사(field research)를 할 수 있게 되고
And there will be an article about me
in the "Paleontology Review"!
또 고생물학 신문 분야에 나오게 되는데,
Yeah! That'll be the first time my name is in there,
without people raising serious questions about my work!
내 연구에 대해서 사람들이 어려운 질문을
하지도 않는데 내 이름이 실리게 된다니까
Wait. Are you talking about the Dewar grant?
잠깐만! 너 듀올 그랜트 말하는 거니?
Yeah. Why?
어! 맞어! 근데 왜?
Benjamin Hobart is administering that grant.
벤자민 호버가 그 그랜트에 책임자거든.
Your ex-boyfriend?
너의 옛날 남자친구 말하는 거니?
Yeah.
응
So, your ex-boyfriend is gonna determine
if your new boyfriend gets this grant?
음. 너의 옛날 남자친구가
새 남자 친구를 심사를 한다...!
Wow, your new boyfriend is screwed!
와우! 너의 새 남자친구는 망했네...
No, no, we ended up in great terms.
그런게 아니야! 우린 아주 깨끗하게 헤어졌어!
I mean, if anything, I think this could help you.
만약 그런게 있다면 아무런 도움이 되지 않을거야!
You know what?
Why don't we all go out to dinner together,
and I can introduce you.
아참! 우리 그 사람이랑 같이 저녁이나 먹지 않을래!
어때! 내가 소개시켜 줄께!
Well, if you think it would help.
만약 그게 도움이 된다면은...
Yes, absolutely. I'll call him.
물론이지. 내가 전화해 놓을께
Ok, now, is there anything I can do to...
you know, butter him up? Anything he really likes?
있지? 내가 어떻게 하면 잘 보일 수 있을지 말해 줄 수 있어?
Mmh... he does have a pretty serious latex fetish.
흠. 그는 심각한 LaTex fetish거든
저녁 식사때 보자구.
We'll see how dinner goes.
Hey!
안녕!
Hey, you wanna go to see a movie?
안녕! 나랑 같이 영화보러 가지 않을래?
Well, I told you I had to spend all the day
clearing out stuff, so Mike could move in.
내가 말 안했나?
이번 주에는 마이크가 이사올 수 있게 짐정리 한다고
Oh, right.
Oh, well. Now that I'm here I might as well help
you with the cleaning and organizing!
맞다.
내가 여기 있는 한 치우는 것을 도와주어야겠네.
그리고 나의 레이블 메이커가 여기에 있군.
Just happen to have my label maker!
Oh, it's so hard to get rid of stuff!
물건들을 버리는 것이 너무 아깝네.
Did you and Chandler have to make compromises when you first moved in together?
챈들러와 같이 살게 되었을 때도 이러했니?
Uh, Chandler did!
난 아니구 챈들러가 그랬지?
What does he want you to give up?
마이크가 어떤 물건을 버리는 것을 원하는데?
A bunch of stuff. And the worst one...
he wants me to get rid of Gladys.
많은 것들이지.
제일 악몽적인 것은 글래디스를 버리는 것을 원해
Who's Gladys?
누가 글래디스인데?
Oh! What a tragic loss!
헉!..... 아주 환상적인 것인데...
Yeah. I really hate to give her up.
그러게! 내가 그녀를 가장 좋아하는 것인데...
Oh, I know!! Oh, you should take her!
맞다! 네가 그녀를 가져가는 거야.
오! 글쎄! 잘 모르겠네!
Well, I-I-I-I... I don't know...
Why, you don't like her?
왜? 싫어?
물론! 좋아하지!
왜 내가 이것을 싫어하겠어!
Well, of course I do.
What's not to like!
I'll take her in a minute!
당장 가져가야지
But, you know, I think that
you're giving up too easy, honey.
I think that you need to fight for her!
이러는 것은 어때? 그렇게 싫으면 타협을 하는거야.
Really? You think?
정말로 그렇게 생각해?
물론이지!
Absolutely! Yes,
이렇게 말해 "미안해 마이크!
you say to him "I'm sorry Mike
I can't live without her,
she means too much to me!"
나 이 물건 도저히 못 버리겠어. 이것은 내가 가장 아끼는 것이야"
Ok, I'll fight for her.
오케이! 타협을 하는거야!
오 맞다! 그러면 네가 그녀를 가지지 못하잖어
Ok! Oh, wait, oh I just realized...
if I do that, that means you don't get her.
내가 왜 그것을 몰랐지!
Damn it, I did not think this through!
Hey you guys.
/Hi!
얘들아!안녕!
/안녕
Oh! Any word on casting yet?
오! 아직 아무런 말이 없니?
Joe, I told you, you're just not right for the part.
조이! 내가 말했잖어!
너는 그 역할에 맞지 않는다구!
What do you mean?
무슨 말이야?
Rach, don't I seem like a professor
you'd buy some kind of e-crap from?
레이철! 네 생각에도 내가 교수역에 안 맞을 거라고 생각해?
I'm sorry, this sounds like something
I'm never gonna be interested in.
미안해! 나는 거기에 관심이 없거든
Look, c'mon, please? It's not like I'm asking for some crazy favour.
이봐! 내가 너한테 무리한 부탁을 하는게 아니잖어.
This is what I do for a living. I am a professional actor!
그게 내가 하는것이고 나는 전문 연기자라구!
Oh, man, I'm two hours late for work!
이런! 일에 두시간이나 늦었네!
Look, here's a copy of my reels.
It's got all the commercials that I've been in.
여기 내가 그동안 광고찍은 것을 녹화한거야
Joe...
/Just watch it, and if you don't like it,
you don't pass it on to your bosses!
조이!
/그냥 보라구! 만약 네가 싫으면 떨어뜨리면 되잖아.
Fine!
/ Thank you.
그래!
/ 고마워!
Work, Joe!
일하러 가야지!
Damn it!
젠장!
What am I gonna do now?
이젠 어떻게 해야되지?
Just pass it to your boss!
그냥! 테이프 보여 주면 되지 않어?
He's not right for the part.
이 역할은 맞지가 않어!
So if I suggest him,
my bosses are gonna think I'm an idiot!
테잎을 보여주면 사장은 나를 바보라고 생각할거야.
And that's something
they should learn on their own!
그것이 바로 무엇인가가 배우는 것이겠지?
Just tell Joey that you watched the tape
and you liked it, but your bosses didn't.
그냥 조이한테 테이프 보았고,
사장이 싫어 했다고 말하면 되잖아
Then that way, you're the good guy
and they're the bad guys.
그럼 너는 좋은 사람이 되는 것이고,
사장은 나쁜 사람이 되는 것이잖아.
That's good! I liked it, they didn't.
그거 괜찮네.
나는 좋아했고, 그들은 싫어했고...
조이! 제발 일하러 가라!
Joey, for God's sake, go to work!
I can't believe I'm about to meet Benjamin Hobart.
내가 벤자민 호버를 만나다니 믿기지가 않네.
I've always thought of him as one of the people
I'd invite to my fantasy dinner party.
내가 그사람을 본건 내 상상속의 파티에서가 전부일줄 알았는데...
Do you think there's any chance
he'll bring Christie Brinkley or C3PO?
그사람이 크리스티 브링클리나 루시 트리피오를 데려오지는 않을까?
Sorry, looks like it's just him.
미안하지만 혼자만 온거 같은데.
Charlie!
찰리!
My God, you look absolutely stunning!
오! 마이 갓! 이 세상에서 가장 아름다운 여자네.
Well, I... I am having a good hair day.
오늘 운수 좋은 날이네요!
So good to see you.
/ Me too.
다시 만나서 반가워!
/ 나도 그래!
mm.. hmmm..
흠...으흠...
난 괜찮아요.
I'm ok.
오! 미안해! 이쪽은 로스 갤러이구 이쪽은 벤자민 호버야
I'm sorry... Ross Geller... Benjamin Hobart.
It's an honor to meet you.
만나서 대단히 영광입니다.
I can't tell you
how long I've been an admirer of your work,
제가 얼마나 당신을 존경하는지 모르실 겁니다.
I mean, that Nobel prize,whoooo!
노벨상에다가...후~~~~우
I mean, I have to tell you that,
you're one of the reasons I got into the field.
당신때문에 고생물학을 하게 된거거든요
Oh, well, likewise. Actually, not likewise.
저도 동의합니다. 동의하지 않습니다.
I've never heard of you until this morning,
사실은 오늘 아침까지 당신이름을 듣지를 못했거든요!
but, it's nice to be nice!
어째든 좋은 것이 좋은게 아니겠습니까?
앉을까요?
/ 그러지
Shall we?
/ Thank you!
고마워요~
Thank you!
I can't believe that you chose this restaurant!
당신이 이 레스토랑을 선택을 했다는 것이 믿어지지가 않는군.
Do you remember the night?
/ Oh my God,
그 날 밤을 기억해?
/ 오! 마이 갓!
I completely forgot!
Oh my God! I can't believe
they let us back in this place!
그 날을 완전히 잊어 버렸네요.
나도 왜 이 레스토랑을 골랐는지 믿기지가 않네요.
당신은 거기에 없었잖소.
You weren't there!
No, but, it's, you know,
it's just a funny image, you know,the two of you,
in this restaurant, with...tzz-zzz, hmmm.
맞아요! 그냥 재미있잖아요! 이 레스토랑 안에서 둘이....흠....
Ross, why don't you tell Benji about your
proposal,while I go to the ladies room?
로스! 내가 화장실에 가 있는 동안 그 이야기 하면 어때?
So, tell me about it.
/OK
한번 말씀해 보시지요!
아직 좋은 사막들이 있어요.
well, I would like to do
a dig in the painted desert.
See, there are still several areas that haven't been fully excavated.
그래서 거기에는 아직 발굴하지 못한 지역이 많이 있습니다.
Break up with Charlie!
그녀와 헤어져요!
예?
/ 뭐?
What?
/ What?
Did you just say "break up with Charlie"?
방금 찰리와 헤어지라고 말씀하셨나요?
Well, yes, and now. Yes I did say it,
and no, I didn't not say it.
네, 아니요. 네 그렇게 말했고, 아니요 그렇게 얘기 안했어요.
Kind of inappropriate, don't you think?
그건 좀 너무하다고 생각하지 않아요?
죄송해요! 이런 감정을 가진 것이 너무 오래 되었고,
I'm sorry. I just haven't seen her for so long!
All these feelings are rushing back! I'm starting to realize how much I missed her,
다시 그 감정으로 가는 것 같아요!
and I'm gonna need you to break up with her.
난 당신이 지금 그녀와 헤어졌으면 하는데요!
Are you serious?
진심인가요?
If you say yes then I'm serious, if you say no then I'm joking!
만약 당신이 그렇다면 그렇고 아니라고 하면 농담이겠지요?
아니요!
No!
Joking it is!
농담이에요!
안녕! 늦어서 미안해!
Hi! Sorry, I'm late.
Hey, how did it go with Mike,
is he gonna let you keep the painting?
마이크랑 어떻게 됐어? 마이크가 허락했니?
No, he really hates it.
아니! 정말이지! 그가 싫어해!
하지만 그가 사람머리카락이든 상자는 가져도 된데,
But he's gonna let me keep my box of human hair!
So you got to pick your battles.
그래서 그가 병을 집었지만,
But the good news is, Gladys is yours!
좋은 소식은 글래디스는 네것이야!
Wow, what's the bad news!
와우! 그럼 나쁜 소식은 뭔데?
Who's Gladys?
글래디스가 누군데?
Oh, she's that work of art I made, you know,
with the woman coming out of the frame.
내가 만든 작품이거든. 이렇게 액자 밖으로 나오는 여자
Oh, and Monica gets to keep her?
모니카가 그 작품을 가진다고.
이 집에다가. 나 무진장 질투가 나네
In her house? I am so jealous!
어! 너도 그 물건을 가지고 싶어하는 줄은 몰랐네!
Oh, I didn't know you wanted her too!
Well, I mean, sure, of course. But...
물론! 하지만 벌써 모니카한테 주었잖아.
you already gave that to Monica, so..
/ I would give her up, for you.
그럴 순 없지.
No, I couldn't let you do that.
하지만 난 원하거든.
But I want to.
But I don't want you to.
그치만 난 싫어.
But I insist!
너한테 줄게.
But I insist harder!
다시 너한테 줄게.
Girls, girls, stop, ok? We'll flip a coin.
얘들아! 그만 싸우고! 동전으로 정하자!
Heads, she's Rachel's, tails she's Monica's.
앞에는 레이첼이구 뒤는 모니카구.
Tails! Monica, she's yours!
뒤부분이 나왔네. 모니카 네것이야.
No, that landed in your food!
그 동전은 네 음식안에 떨어졌다구.
No, no, that's ok. You won fair and square.
I'm so sad!
괜찮아! 아주 정정당당한 승부였어!
나 무지 슬프네!
Hey Joe!
/ What's up?
이봐! 조이
/ 무슨 일이야?
나쁜 소식이야. 내가 너의 테이프를
사장에게 보여 주었지만, 관심이 없데.
Bad news. I watched the tape and passed it along to my bosses and they weren't interested
Oh.
/ I'm sorry man.
그래.
/ 미안하다.
그럼! 너는 이 테이프 봤어?
But, ehm... you watched the tape?
Yeah! I... I... I liked it!
물론이지! 봤지! 아주 괜찮던데!
하지만 내 사장님이 별로라고 하더라구.
But, ehm... my bosses didn't go for it.
개놈의 자식 같으니라구...
Stupid sons of bitches!
너 테이프 보지 않았지?
You didn't watch the tape.
What!? Of course I did!
뭐라구? 당연히 봤지!
Look, it's one thing not to cast me,
but to lie to me?
나를 캐스팅 안하는 것은 괜찮지만,
나한테 거짓말을 해!
I'm not lying to you, I watched it!
나 너한테 거짓말 하는거 아니야.
분명히 봤다구
또 거짓말 하네.
Well, you lied again!
I watched it!
봤다구!!
계속 거짓말 해보라구 피노키오!
Keep going Pinocchio!
I did!
봤다구.
안봤어!
No you didn't!
난 분명히 봤다고 말하는 거라구
I'm telling you, I watched the tape.
너 그 테이프 봤어?
Did you watch the tape?
아니~
No!
The selection committee has chosen the three of you as our finalists today.
이렇게 와주셔서 감사합니다.
오늘 세분은 제가 질문하는 것에
답을 말씀 해주시면 됩니다.
The ultimate decision will be based upon the answers you give to the questions I ask here.
I'm gonna start with Dr. Li.
그럼 리박사님부터 시작하지요.
Dr. Li, you claim the field is too reliant on the Linnaean taxonomic system.
리박시님! 분류학법 시스템에 대해서 말씀해주시겠습니까?
How do you propose to correct this problem?
이 시스템에 대해 어떤 제안을 주시겠습니까?
Well, I believe that the answers lie in the osteological evidence.
제가 생각을 하기에는 아티어 로지컬 에버던스는 거짓이라고 봅니다.
그래서 그곳에서부터 시작을 하는 것이 저의 계획입니다.
/ 재미있군요
I plan to begin there.
/ Interesting.
그렇겠군요.
I guess!
Dr. Biely, your proposal includes some field work. Where might that take place?
바얼리 박사님!
현장 탐사를 계획하시는곳이 어느 지방이시지요?
Primarily in the Pierre Shale region of South Dakota.
주로 사우스 다코타 주에서 작업하게 됩니다.
좋습니다.
Certainly. Very well.
And Dr. Geller, when is my birthday?
갤러 박사님! 제 생일이 언제입니까?
What? I... I...
뭐라구요? 저......
짐작이라도 함 해 보지요?
Care to venture a guess?
May 12th?
5월 12일이요!
근접하지도 않네요.
That's not even kinda close!
Dr. Li, how many graduate students you'd be needing?
리박사님! 연구원생들이 얼마나 필요하시지요?
Half a dozen.
6명 필요합니다.
I see, and Dr. Biely?
바얼리 박사님?
Three for excavation and two for analysis.
3명의 활동 대원들과 2명의 탐사 조사관입니다.
Certainly. Dr. Geller,
겔러박사님!
which 1965 Shirelles hit was later covered by a popular British invasion band?
영국의 인기있는 인베이젼 밴드 슈렐스의 1965년 힛트곡은?
Wha..? I need 6 graduate students.
뭐라구요! 저는 6명의 졸업생이 필요합니다.
No! I'm sorry, we were looking for "Baby It's You".
그건 내가 원하는 답이 아니군요, 답은 baby it's you입니다. "baby it's you"
Baby It's You.
저기! 잠시만요!
왜 저에게는 고생물학에 대해서는 묻지않는거지요?
Wha...? Wait, wait, wait, just a minute.
None of my questions have anything to do with Paleontology.
You're right, I apologize.
Scratch the last question.
맞아요! 죄송합니다. 마지막 질문을 드릴께요!
Spell "Mboscodictiosaur".
바스코딕티올 사우루스에 대해서 철자를 함 대보세요
um... I've never heard of a "Mboscodictiosaur".
저는 거기에 대해 들은 적이 없는데요!
Yeah, I just made it up. Spell it.
방금 말했잖아요! 철자 한번 대보세요
Ok! b.o.m
좋아요! b.o.m
No, it starts with a silent "M".
첫글자는 묵음 m인데요.
이봐요!
Oh come on!!
I can't believe Joey.
조이가 그렇게 나오다니 믿을 수가 없어.
I hate being called a liar!
거짓말쟁이라고 부르는 것은 참을 수가 없어.
But you are a liar.
하지만 넌 거지말쟁이잖아
What did I just say?
내가 방금 무슨 말을 했는데?
아직도 여기에 있는거냐?
You still here?
그래. 내가 말하는데 나는 결백해.
Yes, and I have to say, I am not just hurt.
I am insulted.
When I tell somebody I did something...
Ok whoah-hey... Let me just stop you right there, ok? First, you lied, right?
잠깐만! 첫 번째로 너는 거짓말을 했고...맞지...
Then, you lied about lying, ok?
그리고 거짓에 대해 거짓말을 했고,
또 그 거짓말에 거짓말에 거짓말을 했고,
다시 거짓에 거짓에........
Then you lied about lying about lying, ok?
So before you lie about lying about lying about lying about... lying...
Stop lying!
제발 거짓말 좀 그만해.
왜 그렇게 확신을 가지는 거야?
Why are you so sure I didn't watch this tape?
그렇게 알고 싶어?
You wanna know wh...? You wanna know why?
이거 잘되가는데.
Well, this is going well.
Here's how I know you didn't watch the tape, ok?
네가 테이프를 보지 않았다는 것을 증명해 보이지.
만약 네가 이 테이프를 보았다면 너는 여기에 대해 무엇인가 이야기를 했을 거야.
If you had seen what was on this tape,
believe me, you would have some comments.
Alright, now remember, I got paid a lot of money for this and it only aired in Japan.
명심해 둘 것은 내가 이것을 만드는데 투자를 많이 했고,
이 방송은 일본만 나가는 거야.
"いちばん(ichibann)"
이치방...(일본어로 최고라는 뜻입니다.)
"いちばん(ichibann)" "Lipstick For Men!"
이치방...이것은 남성용입니다.
"いちばん(ichbann)... Lipstick For Men".
이치방...이것은 남성용입니다....
"さいこう(sahiko)"
사이고
(역시 일본어로 최고라는 뜻입니다.)
And that's how I know you didn't watch the tape!
그래서. 내가 너보고 이 테이프를 보지 않았다는 거야
He really is a chameleon.
정말 카멜레온이네.
글래디스! 새로운 집에 온 것을 환영한다.
Well, Gladys say hello to your new home!
오!마이!
Oh, my!
와우! 굉장히 이쁘고 크네
Wow! Oh, she's so nice and big!
Oh, Monica, where are you going to display Gladys oh so proudly?
오! 모니카! 글래디스를 어디에다가 놓을까?
아직 생각을 안해봐서 모르겠는데...
I haven't really settled on a spot yet!
그럼 TV위에다가 걸어 놓는 것은 어떨까?
Well, hey! How about right above the TV?
That way, it will be the first thing that
you see when you walk in the door!
그러면 문에 들어와서 처음으로 보는게 저거겠네
그래 맞어!
저거 프랜치 포스터를 없애 버리면 되겠네...
Yeah, yeah!
And you can get rid of that French poster...
내가 좋아하는 포스터 인데
I like that poster!
정말? 저기선 튀어나오는 것도 없는데?
Really? It doesn't have anything coming out of it.
Or maybe there is some place
for her in your bedroom?
그럼! 침실에다가 두면 되겠네!
그러면 침대위에 달아 두면 되겠네!
Oh! There's nothing above your bed!!
너 아직도 여기에 있는거냐?
Are you still here?
Oh hi! Hello! Uh, have you come to ask me
some more paleontology related questions?
오! 안녕하세요?
저에게 아직도 고생물학 분류법에 대해 물어 볼것이 있나요?
오! 당신의 할머니 이름이라든지?
팬티사이즈라든지?
Uhm... your grandmother's nickname, perhaps?
Aunt Margaret's pants size?
제가 여기에 온 것은 사과하기 위해서입니다.
I've come here to apologize.
I think I may have let my feelings
for Charlie interfere with the interview process.
제가 찰리에대한 감정을 인터뷰할 때 조금 드러낸 것 같습니다.
No! Stop!
괜찮아요!
Anyway, I've decided to offer you the grant.
그래서 당신이 그랜트를 타시는 것을 결정을 하였습니다.
Really?
정말로요?
Well... there is just one small... stipulation...
글쎄요! 아주 조그마한 조건이 있긴 한데요!
I have to break up with Charlie?
제가 찰리하고 헤어지는 조건인가요?
맞아요!
Hey, you got one right!
You're crazy.
당신 미쳤군요!
Crazy, or... romantic?
미친것인가요 아니면 로맨틱한것인가요?
Crazy!
미쳤어요!
Ooor...
/ Get out!
아니면...
/ 당장 나가요!
O-oh my God!
오!마이 갓!
What?
왜!
Joey, what... is... this...thing... doing here?
조이! 이것이 왜 여기에 있는거야?
I got it from Monica. She sold it to me
for a very reasonable price.
모니카한테 샀어.걔가 아주 괜찮은 가격에 나한테 팔았거든...
Joey, we're not keeping this!
조이! 우린 이거 가질 수가 없어.
But it's an original Buffay...
하지만 괜찮은 가격에 부페의 수제품이란 말야.
Alright, fine. You can keep it.
좋아! 가져도 돼!
만약 얘가 너를 잡어 먹지 않는 다면 말이야.
As long as you don't mind that she's haunted.
뭐! 뭐! 뭐라구!
Hey? what? what? wey! whoo! what? what!?
Well, legend has it Joey, that...
she comes alive when you're asleep.
글쎄! 전설에 따르면 네가 잠이 들 때 너를 덥치거든.
She climbs out of the frame,
얘가 프레임밖으로 나와서 머리도 밖으로 반쯤 나오고,
and then drags her half-a-body across the floor,
바닥을 기어 다니며 다리가 어디로 갔나 하면서 찾아다니지...
looking for legs to steal.
And then with her one good hand, she slo-o-owly re-e-a-aches up and turns your doorknob.
아주 상태가 좋은 손으로 문을 살짝 틀어서...
GET THAT LEGLESS WITCH OUT OF HERE!
여기서 당장 글래디스를 버려 버리라구.
이봐! 내가 조이한테 팔았다구.
Hey! I sold that to Joey.
Well, why I told him it's haunted. Two can play at this game.
내가 조이한테 잡아 먹힐 거라구 말했다.
No, too late. You can't give it back!
/ Yes I can!
너무 늦어서! 지금은 다시 못가지고 들어와!
/ 할 수 있어
No you can't. She's yours!
/She's yours!
할 수 없어! 이것은 네꺼잖아.
/원래는 네꺼였잖아.
SHE'S YOURS!
/ She's yours!
네꺼야.
/ 네꺼야.
안녕
Hey!
She's mine!
/She's m-i-i-ne!
내꺼야.
/내꺼야.
You guys! You guys! You don't have to fight over her anymore.
얘들아 이제 그만 싸워도 돼...
Whoever doesn't get Gladys gets Glynnis.
누군가 그 글래디스를 가지면
여기 또 하나의 글래디스가 있어.
I want Gladys!
/ She's mine!
이거 내꺼야.
/ 내꺼라니까
Look, I'm sorry I didn't give them your tape.
이봐! 그 테이프를 사장한테 전해주지 않은 것은 정말 미안하다.
And I promise, next time to submit you whether I think you are right for the part or not.
다음번에는 꼭 역할을 주겠다고 약속할게.
그것이 요점이 아니야! 챈들러!
요점은 거짓말을 했다는거야
That's not the point Chandler. The point is that you lied.
I know. You're right. What's it gonna take for you to forgive me?
나도 알어! 네 말이 맞어!
어떻게 하면 나를 용서 해 줄 수 있겠냐?
오! 마이 갓!
Oh my God!
아주 훌륭해!
Excellent!
Now, what do you say?
내가 뭐라고 했지?
거짓말은 잘못된 것이다.
Lying is wrong!.
And?... AND?
그리고....그리고
나는 작은 소녀다.
I'm a pretty little girl.
I knew it!
나는 알고 있었어!
Your ex-boyfriend is insane.
너의 옛날 남자친구는 미쳤어!
Did you get the grant?
그랜트 탔어?
No I didn't, and you want to know why?
아니 타지 못했어! 그 이유를 알고 싶어?
Because your ex-boyfriend is still in love with you.
너의 옛날 남자 친구가 아직도 널 사랑하고 있어.
What?
뭐라고?
Yeah. He wouldn't give me the grant, because I wouldn't give you up.
맞아! 내가 너를 포기 하지 않아서 주지 못한다는 거야.
벤지는 나를 사랑하지 않어. 그가 나를 찼고
Benji isn't in love with me.
I mean, he broke up with me.
And besides, he's a very ethical man.
그리고 그는 아주 정정당당한 사람이야.
Really?
정말로? 그럼 그렇게
정정당당한 사람이 그런 식으로 질문을 하는 거야?
Is it ethical to ask someone in a grant review,
who was the voice of "Underdog"?
I'm sure he was just joking, Ross
내가 확신하는데 농담이었을 거야.
If you don't believe me,
let's go talk to him, okay? I'm telling you,
네가 나를 믿지 못하겠다면 지금 당장 가서 이야기하러 가자
He didn't ask me one paleontological question.
나에게 단 한가지도 고생물학에 대해서 질문을 안했어.
Seriously?
정말로?
Oh, I'm sorry, no. He did ask me one?
오! 미안해! 한 가지 질문을 했었지?
바스코딕티올 사우루스 의 철자가 어떻게 되는지요?
Uhm... How do you spell Mboscodictiosaur?
글쎄. 바스코딕티올 사우루스라면 철자가 m. b. o...
Well, if it's like the lake Mbosco in Congo, then M-B-O...
Damn it!
젠장!
Dr. Geller...?
Charlie... What are you...
what are you doing here?
갤러 박사님!
찰리! 여기서 뭐하는 거야!
이 여자에게 모든 것을 말해 주길 바래요!
I want you to tell her everything.
About the deal you tried to make with me,
about the crazy questions you... Wally Cox!
당신이 나에게 질문을 했던 것처럼 말입니다.
That's the voice of Underdog!
Like I tried to tell you in the interview Ross, this grant is not based on your knowledge of pretty useless trivia.
로스! 나는 말하지요!
이번 그랜트는 그런 쪽의 지식에 기반해서 주는게 아니에요.
No, no, no. Don't do that! I want you to look her in the eyes, and tell her the truth.
그런식으로 하지 말아요.
찰리의 눈을 바라보며 진실대로 말해주세요
벤지?
Benji?
Alright, it's true.
맞아! 사실이야.
내가 그렇게 행동을 했던 것은
아직도 찰리를 사랑하기 때문이야.
I behaved horribly. But it's only because I still love you.
And I would do anything to have you back in my life.
당신을 다시 돌려받을 수만 있다면 뭐든지할거야.
Too little, too late, Benji!
너무 늦었어요! 벤지
믿어지지가 않는군요!
I can't believe this.
I never should have broken up with you.
내가 잘못 생각 해서 당신과 헤어졌어.
I think about you all the time.
I mean, do you ever still think about me?
매일 당신을 생각했어.
아직도 나에 대해 감정이 있어?
아뇨
No!
Yes!
그럼요.
What?
뭐라고?
I don't know what to say, Benji. This is all so.... romantic.
네. 뭐라고 말을 해야 좋을지 모르겠지만,
이것도 상당히 로멘틱 하군요
아니면
or...
Listen, I know, I may be way out of bounds here,
but is there any chance you will take me back?
내가 실수를 했다는 것은 알어!
다시 한번만 기회를 주지 않겠어!
아마도요!
Maybe...
자기야! 좀 불편한데 잠깐 이야기좀 할까?
Sweetie, this conversation is starting
to make me a little uncomfortable.
오! 미안해 우리 둘 사이 관계에 대해 이야기가 길어
Oh God! I am so sorry, but...I mean it's...
there's so much history between us, you know...
저도 미안하군요!
I'm sorry too...
I love you!
/ I love you too!
사랑해~
/ 저도 사랑해요!
Okay, that's it. WE ARE SEEING OTHER PEOPLE!
이것으로 됐습니다.
우리 각자 서로 다른 길로 갑시다.
글래디스
Gladys?
아~~~~악!
Ha ha ha, third time this week. Man, this does not get old.
아하! 놀랬지!
너무 하는군.
You're mean!
Oh, don't be such a baby!
그렇게 애처럼 굴지마~
아~~~~악